**Terms and Conditions / Privacy Policy**

Search results provided by Google SafeSearch with additional keyword filtering by KidzSearch.com. KidzSearch offers no guarantees or warranties on results. Please [contact us](https://www.kidzsearch.com/contactus.html) if you have any specific issues or concerns about results found. 

KidzSearch believes that maintaining the online privacy of children is essential to building a safe site where kids can learn and play. We provide the following information about our policies in conformance with the 1998 Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). **  
  
1\. What personal information does KidzSearch collect?**

KidzSearch does not collect visitors' personally identifiable information without consent, nor does KidzSearch require visitors to give personally identifiable information in order to access or use our site. KidzSearch will not require a visitor to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of that participation. The KidzSearch site contains links to other Web sites that may ask for personal information. Although we try to review such sites carefully, KidzSearch expressly disclaims any responsibility or liability for their privacy policies, data collection practices or regulatory compliance of those independent sites. Certain features of our site may require entering an email address to submit content, or to be notified about getting a response to a forum (KidzTalk) question. Users are given clear instructions that this is optional, and if they want to participate they must be over 13 years of age, or have their parents [contact us](https://www.kidzsearch.com/contactus.html) for consent. Personal information, such as full names, phone numbers, or address details are never collected. Following COPPA exclusions, our [contact form](https://www.kidzsearch.com/contactus.html) allows one-time responses from us to user questions and we never store e-mails after a response is given back.

**2\. Does KidzSearch use cookies?**

Yes, but only to provide generic non-personal site features, such as remembering a selected background screen color when a person visits again. We do not store any identifiable information.

**3\. Does KidzSearch collect aggregated information?**

KidzSearch collects statistics on which keywords a visitor searches and which responses they select. This information is gathered together (aggregated) so that individual visitors cannot be identified or distinguished from the whole. The same is true for websites visited (see Filtering API and Data section below). For example, we might know that 100 visitors searched for giraffes, but we do not know who those visitors were. This information helps us make editorial and design decisions to make KidzSearch more helpful, such as providing better autocomplete. As required by COPPA, we do not show any ads that are interest-based. We only allow ads that are contextual, meaning it is related to the page a user is viewing and not based on any identifiable information or past sites visited. This is done by opting-out of this feature with our ad network partners.

We may use aggregated information to help us target advertising or content based on general location or other non-identifiable data. We also may collect IP Addresses (which domain a visitor is logged on from), Referral Data (the address of the last URL a user visited prior to clicking through to KidzSearch), Browser type (which browser is being used), Platform Type (whether a visitor uses Macintosh or Windows), and Traffic Flow (where a visitor spends their time while on the site) on our site, however these collected pieces of information do not allow for personal identification of the visitor.

**4\. Does KidzSearch have a chat room?**

No.

**5\. Does KidzSearch run contests for children?**

We may have periodic contests.  Collected information is never given out to third-parties and parental permission is always required.  
  
**6\. Interaction with Children  
  
**The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) governs information gathering online from or about children under the age of 13. Verifiable consent from a child's parent or guardian is required before collecting, using, or disclosing personal information from a child under the age of 13.  
  
We collect no identifiable personal information, like email, address, first/last name, etc. for users that are under 13 years of age. None of our features require an account for usage. However, some features have added-value items, like notification if a homework help question is answered. These special features require parental consent for children under 13 before it can be used and we communicate this to the user. If we do need to collect information about a child under 13 years of age, COPPA required information and instructions will be provided by the specific Web page that collects information about the child. The Web page will specify exactly what the information will be used for, who will see it, and how long it will be kept. We never ask or store personal information, such as email address or full names of our subscribers. The only email stored is a the parent's account, since that is needed to get membership approval. Account requests that are not activated are deleted after 21 days. Finally, all posted content is first reviewed by staff for safety, such as if it contains any personal or harmful content. If it does, the content is either edited to make it safe, or removed from our system.

There are several exceptions that permit collection of a child's email address without receiving parental consent in advance:  
  
To provide the parents with notice and to seek consent for communications with the child. Note: this may require collection of the parent's email address as well.  
  
To respond to a one time request from a child, such as when they user our contact form.  
  
To respond more than once to a child's request; i.e., subscription to a newsletter. However, parental consent is required prior to the second communication.  
  
To protect the safety of a child who is participating on the site; i.e., in our homework help forum.  
  
To protect the site or to respond to law enforcement; i.e., in the case of a Web site being compromised.  
  
Personal information about children under 13 years of age may be needed to respond to his/her communication to us, such as to request a site feature or to report problems with the site. Personal information about your child will be deleted/destroyed immediately upon completion of its intended purpose. On rare occasions, it may be determined that a communication from a child under 13 years old should be maintained for historical purposes. Should such an occasion occur, we will obtain the necessary consent from the child's parent.  
  
**6\. How can I contact KidzSearch if I have questions about this Privacy Policy?**

If you have any questions about the KidzSearch Privacy Policy, [email us](https://www.kidzsearch.com/contactus.html).  
  
**TERMS AND CONDITIONS**  
  
PLEASE READ THESE TERMS, CONDITIONS AND POLICIES CAREFULLY. This Web site, KidzSearch.com, is offered to you, the user, on the full acceptance of the terms, conditions, and policies contained herein. By visiting this site, or using any of our services constitutes your agreement to all terms, conditions, and policies. If you do not agree with any of the contained terms conditions or policies, please leave this site immediately.  
  
**LIMITATIONS**  
This Web site is for your personal and non-commercial use in accordance with the terms and conditions of this agreement, and as a condition of your use you warrant and represent to KidzSearch that you will not use this Web site for any illegal purpose or for any purpose that is prohibited by the terms and conditions of this agreement. Specifically, you may not modify, copy, distribute, transmit, publish, display, license, create derivative works from or sell any product, services, information or software obtained from this Web site.  
  
**APPLICABLE LAWS**  
By using or visiting KidzSearch, you agree that the internal laws of the State of California, without regard to the principles of conflicts of laws, will govern this agreement and any dispute of any kind that arises between you and KidzSearch, its affiliates or partners. You hereby agree that any dispute arising from or relating to the use of this Web site will be subject to binding arbitration under the commercial rules of the American Arbitration Association. The arbitration shall be conducted in Ventura County, California, USA before neutral arbitrators. Use of this Web site is unauthorized in any jurisdiction that does not give effect to all provisions of this agreement, including, but not limited, to this paragraph.  
  
If any provision of these terms and conditions is determined to be invalid or unenforceable pursuant to applicable law by any court of competent jurisdiction, the other provisions of this agreement will remain in full force and effect. Any provision of this agreement held to be invalid or unenforceable, including but not limited to the warranty disclaimers and liability limitations set forth above, will be deemed superseded by a valid, enforceable provision that most closely matches the intent of the original provision.  
  
KidzSearch' fulfillment of this agreement is subject to existing laws. Nothing contained in this agreement is in derogation of KidzSearch' right to abide to and comply with law enforcement requests or requirements relating to your use of this Web site or information provided to or gathered by KidzSearch with respect to your used of this Web site.  
  
As a condition of your use of this Web site, you warrant that you will not use this Web site for any purpose that is unlawful or prohibited by these terms, conditions, and notices.  
  
**NAI/IAB**  
We are compliant with the policies of several industry groups that focus on effective communication, best practices, and policy review in the field of Online Behavioral Advertising (OBA). These organizations include the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA), and the Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB). We are compliant with both the NAI and DAA self-regulatory codes. We believe that delivering targeted and relevant advertising enhances your internet experience. While we only include advertisers and ad networks that are COPPA compliant, other websites you visit outside of the KidzSearch.com domain may contain behavioral or interest based ads. You can opt-out from getting interest based ads using the following link [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  
  
**COMMUNICATION**  
You communicate with KidzSearch whenever you visit KidzSearch.com or send an email and/or fax to us. You consent to receive communications from KidzSearch electronically and/or by fax. We will communicate with you by posting notices on this site, sending an email and/or fax. You agree that all notices, disclosures, terms, agreements and other communications provided to you electronically or by fax by KidzSearch satisfy any legal requirements that communications be in writing.  
  
**THIRD PARTY WEB SITES**  
This web site may contain inks to web sites operated by parties other than KidzSearch. Such third party links are provided for your reference and convenience only. KidzSearch does not operate or control such web sites and is not responsible for their content, products, or services. Our inclusion of links to such Web sites does not imply any endorsement of the content, products, or services on such web sites or any association with their operators.  
  
**ADVERTISING**  
KidzSearch may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads. In response to current COPPA rules, KidzSearch.com does not run or accept any behaviorally targeted ads. Behavioral ads are advertisements that track specific websites visited to determine which ads to display. The only ads we allow are contextually-based ads, or other types of ads that are not based on a tracking where a user has been on their browser.  
  
KidzSearch does not run behaviorally targeted ads. However, if you want to opt out of these on other websites that do have them, you can visit the following link: [http://www.iab.net/privacymatters/](https://www.iab.net/privacymatters/)  
  
While advertising to this site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique cookie or web beacon on your browser. However, they are not using this information in any way to track users with respect to ads shown, since we do not allow behavioral advertising. Any information collected by them is anonymous and just used to help them run internal operations. Information about visitors, such as the number of times they have viewed an ad (but not a users name, address, or other personal information), is used to control the delivery of ads on this site for internal operations and is permitted by COPPA. An advertiser may also look at the content of a page to deliver more relevant advertising, which is also permitted.  
  
You can view the privacy policies for each ad company we run by following the links below:

Google: [Google AdSense](https://policies.google.com/) - We are set to only show ads without tracking.  
  
SuperAwesome: [AwesomeAds](https://www.superawesome.com/privacy-hub/awesomeads-privacy-policy/)  
  
**ANALYTICS**  
KidzSearch tracks user activity for reporting purposes, but only collects non-identifiable IP addresses. This is sent to our partner, Google.com for analytics reporting in order to maintain our internal operations as permitted by COPPA.  
  
**SEARCH DATA**  
User search terms are stored, but never linked to any identifiable users. The information is used for internal operations, such as providing intelligent autocomplete search. This data is also supplied to our search partner, Google.com without any identifiable information besides the keyword.  
  
**SOCIAL MEDIA PLUGINS**  
KidzSearch protects privacy by not using social media sharing plugins.  

**FILTERING API AND DATA**  
Certain KidzSearch features, such as our app website safety filtering, use third-party services. Links related to YouTube use their API. By using our service you must also agree to [YouTube's Terms of Service](https://www.youtube.com/t/terms) and [Google's Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy). Information is only used to determine the safety of a link. Unless permission is given to us by a parent/guardian for special services, such as monitoring content viewed, we do not store this information. However, we may cache it for a short amount of time for performance reasons, but do not associate it with any personally identifiable data. For example, if we know a certain video is safe to view, we may keep this information for 24 hours to make our site faster for other similar requests. We do not share this information with any external parties and only use it for internal services.  
  
**LIABILITY DISCLAIMER**  
THE INFORMATION, PRODUCTS, AND SERVICES PUBLISHED ON THIS WEB SITE MAY INCLUDE INACCURACIES OR TYPOGRAPHICAL ERRORS. CHANGES ARE PERIODICALLY ADDED TO THE INFORMATION HEREIN. KidzSearch, ITS AFFILIATES, AND/OR THEIR RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS MAY MAKE IMPROVEMENTS AND/OR CHANGES ON THIS WEB SITE AT ANY TIME.  
  
KidzSearch, ITS AFFILIATES, AND/OR THEIR RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE INFORMATION, PRODUCTS, AND SERVICES CONTAINED ON THIS WEB SITE FOR ANY PURPOSE. ALL SUCH INFORMATION, PRODUCTS, AND SERVICES ARE PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. KidzSearch, ITS AFFILIATES, AND/OR THEIR RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS HEREBY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS WITH REGARD TO THIS INFORMATION, PRODUCTS, AND SERVICES, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL KidzSearch, ITS AFFILIATES, AND/OR THEIR RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF, OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH, THE USE OF THIS WEB SITE OR WITH THE DELAY OR INABILITY TO USE THIS WEB SITE, OR FOR ANY INFORMATION, PRODUCTS, AND SERVICES OBTAINED THROUGH THIS WEB SITE, OR OTHERWISE ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF THIS WEB SITE, WHETHER BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR OTHERWISE, EVEN IF KidzSearch, ITS AFFILIATES, AND/OR THEIR RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF DAMAGES. BECAUSE SOME STATES/JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, THE ABOVE LIMITATION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.  

**COPYRIGHT AND TRADEMARK NOTICES**  
This web site is owned and operated by, and the contents of this Web site are copyrighted by KidzSearch. All rights reserved. KidzSearch, variations of this word mark, and the KidzSearch logo are registered trademarks of KidzSearch. Other product, service or company names mentioned herein may be the trademarks of their respective owners.  
  
**Copyright and Limited License**  
Unless otherwise indicated, the Site and all content and other materials on the Site, including, without limitation, the KidzSearch logo, and all designs, text, graphics, pictures, information, data, software, sound files, other files and the selection and arrangement thereof (collectively, the "Site Materials") are the proprietary property of KidzSearch or its licensors or users and are protected by U.S. and international copyright and/or other intellectual property laws.  
  
You are granted a limited, non-sublicensable license to access and use the Site and electronically copy (except where prohibited without a license) and print to hard copy portions of the Site Materials solely for your informational, non-commercial and personal use, or to purchase KidzSearch products. Such license is subject to these Site Terms and does not include: (a) any resale or commercial use of the Site or the Site Materials therein; (b) the collection and use of any product listings, pictures or descriptions; (c) the distribution, public performance or public display of any Site Materials, (d) modifying or otherwise making any derivative uses of the Site and the Site Materials, or any portion thereof; (e) use of any data mining, robots or similar data gathering or extraction methods; (f) downloading (other than page caching) of any portion of the Site, the Site Materials or any information contained therein, except as expressly permitted on the Site; or (g) any use of the Site or the Site Materials other than for its intended purpose. Any use of the Site or the Site Materials other than as specifically authorized herein, without the prior written permission of KidzSearch, is strictly prohibited and will terminate the license granted herein. Such unauthorized use may also violate applicable laws including without limitation copyright and trademark laws and applicable communications regulations and statutes. Unless explicitly stated herein, nothing in these Site Terms shall be construed as conferring any license to intellectual property rights, whether by estoppel, implication or otherwise. This license is revocable at any time.  
  
**Repeat Infringer Policy**  
In accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) and other applicable law, KidzSearch has adopted a policy of terminating, in appropriate circumstances and at KidzSearch's sole discretion, subscribers or account holders who are deemed to be repeat infringers. KidzSearch may also at its sole discretion limit access to the Site and/or terminate the accounts of any users who infringe any intellectual property rights of others, whether or not there is any repeat infringement.  
  
**Copyright Complaints**  
If you believe that anything on the Site infringes any copyright which you own or control please [contact us](https://www.kidzsearch.com/contactus.html) about and we will promptly remove it.  
  
Please see 17 U.S.C. 512(c)(3) for the requirements of a proper notification. Please note that the information provided in your notification, including any personal information contained therein, may be forwarded to the person who has provided the allegedly infringing content, and your sending us such notification constitutes your consent to share this information with the alleged infringer.  
  
You should also note that if you make any misrepresentation in your notification that the material or activity is infringing, you will be liable for all damages, including costs and attorneys' fees, incurred by us or the alleged infringer as the result of our relying upon such misrepresentation in removing or disabling access to the material or activity claimed to be infringing.  
  
We may give notice of a claim of copyright infringement to our users by means of a general notice on the Site, e-mail to a user's e-mail address in our records, or by written communication sent by first-class mail to a user's address in our records.  
  
**Trademarks**  
KidzSearch, the KidzSearch logo, and any other product or service name or slogan contained in the Site are trademarks of KidzSearch (and/or its suppliers or licensors as indicated), and may not be copied, imitated or used, in whole or in part, without the prior written permission of KidzSearch or the applicable trademark holder. You may not use any metatags or any other "hidden text" utilizing "KidzSearch" or any other name, trademark or product or service name of KidzSearch without our prior written permission. In addition, the look and feel of the Site, including all page headers, custom graphics, button icons and scripts, is the service mark, trademark and/or trade dress of KidzSearch and may not be copied, imitated or used, in whole or in part, without our prior written permission. All other trademarks, registered trademarks, product names and company names or logos mentioned in the Site are the property of their respective owners. Reference to any third-party products, services, processes or other information, by trade name, trademark, manufacturer, supplier or otherwise does not constitute or imply endorsement, sponsorship or recommendation by KidzSearch.  
  
MODIFICATION OF THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS KidzSearch reserves the right to change, modify or amend any of these terms, conditions, and notices under which this Web site is offered without prior notices.  

Copyright 2005-2024 KidzSearch.com
